Guide to the Richard Moore Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1943-2007; Series III; (16 boxes)
  - Writings of Others
    - Various Authors, 1980s; 2 (Box 36)
      Includes work by: Lila Chalpin, Ruth Cigman, Bill Costley, Nancy Davies, Murray Denofsky, Nancy Bruno, Bob Dylan, Edison Dupree, Kenneth George Mills, Art Edelstein, Gene Eglin, William Ferguson, Jane Greer and Patti Hagan.
    - Hodges, Elizabeth (Box 36)
    - Various Authors (Box 36)
      Includes work by: Peter J. Hodgson, Judson Jerome, Rodney Jones, William Joyce, Howard Wilcox, Martin Krieger, Christopher L'Estrang and Stephen Lewis.
    - Lightman, Alan P. (Box 36)
    - Lisker, Roy, 1980 (Box 36)
    - Various Authors (Box 36)
      Includes work by: Kurt Loell, Frank Lonergan, Colin Mahoney and Charles Martin.
    - McAlpine, Katherine (Box 36)
    - Various Authors, 5 (Box 36)
      Includes work by: Harold Grier McCurdy, Sherryll Mleynek, David Montenegro, William H. Nolte, Nori Odoi, Marianne Ozernoy, Kathryn Pappas, Youngsuk Park, Marian Parry, Victor Perera, Daniel Pinkham, Hamo Sahyan, Andrea Santillo, Chris Sawyer-Laucanno, John Searle, Frank A. Shefton, Arvid Shulenberger, Arthur Shurcliff, Michael Stillman, Rowland Sturges, Stanley Sultan, David Travis, "Truth and Beauty (Erika Mumford's Workshop), Kathryn Van Spanckeren, Richard Waring, Victor Weiskopf, Joan Wolf, Bill White, and Baron Wormser.
- Journal, 1956-2007; Series IV; (2 boxes)
  Series IV. consists of Moore's journal, which is comprised of loose-leaf pages, written on both sides and compiled into sixteen "volumes" and three "levels." Each level was originally supported by a wooden base with strings on the top and bottom ends for maneuvering. The levels were stacked one on top of the other in a cardboard box with the first level ("L1") on the bottom and the third level ("L3") on the top; and the volumes were stacked in reverse chronological order on each level. For example, "L1" contained Volumes I to VI, with Volume I on the bottom and Volume VI on the top. For preservation and access purposes, the journal pages have been rehoused in acid-free folders. But the original dividers and cardboard box have been retained for reference and study purposes.
  - Notes and List (Box 37)
  - L1, Volume I, 1956-1957 (Box 37)
  - L1, Volume II, 1958 (Box 37)
  - L1, Volume III, 1959-1960 (Box 37)
  - L1, Volume IV, 1960 (Box 37)
  - L1, Volume V, 1960-1962 (Box 37)
  - L1, Volume VI, 1962-1964 (Box 37)
  - L1, Divider (Box 37)
  - L2, Volume VII, 1964-1967 (Box 37)
  - L2, Volume VIII, 1967-1969 (Box 37)
  - L2, Volume IX, 1970-1971 (Box 37)
  - L2, Volume X, 1972-1975 (Box 37)
  - L2, Volume XI, 1976-1984 (Box 37)
  - L2, Divider (Box 37)
  - L3, Volume XII, 1985-1988 (Box 37)
  - L3, Volume XIII, 1989-1992 (Box 37)
  - L3, Volume XIV, 1993-1996 (Box 37)
  - L3, Volume XV, 1997-2002 (Box 37)
  - L3, Volume XVI, 2003-2007 (Box 37)
  - L3, Divider (Box 37)
  - Original box from which journal was removed (Box 38)
- Other Papers, 1940s-2007; Series V; (3 boxes)
  Arranged in no particular order.
  Series V. includes copies of Moore's published books with his annotations, student papers, notes, and other papers.
  - Annotated books by Richard Moore
    - Bottom Is Back, 1994 (Box 39)
    - Empires, 1981 (Box 39)
    - The Investigator, 1991 (Box 39)
  - Family Papers (Box 40)
  - Brandeis University, 1976-1977 (Box 41)
  - Wormser, Baron, 1980s-1990s (Box 41)
  - "Archive for Nancy Kuhl" (notes regarding the donation and transfer of his collection to the Beinecke Library), 2009 (Box 41)
  - Old Class Notes, 1940s-1970s
    - Van De Mer, La Dentelliere cutout (Box 42)
    - The Histomap of Religion, by John B. Sparks
    - Poems on ditto sheet and pencilled sheet music (Box 42)
    - "Test, etc." (Box 42)
    - A Syllabus of Readings in English Literature, by John F. Leisher, 1950 (Box 42)
    - Poems, ditto sheets (Box 42)
    - Treasures of Massachusetts, Boston Globe., 1972 March 5
    - Poems, ditto sheets & the MLA style sheet (Box 42)
    - The Histomap of Evolution, by John B. Sparks
    - Criticism (Morse) (Box 42)
    - Criticism (Bertocci) (Box 42)
    - 18th Century (Williams) (Box 42)
    - First trip to Europe; Air Force stuff (Box 42)
    - Restoration Drama - Berman (Box 42)
    - Greek Drama (Box 42)
    - Classical Civilization (Box 42)
    - Greek and Elizabethan drama (Box 42)
    - Correspondence, 1950s (Box 42)
    - Geology (Box 42)
    - Sociology, 1948 (Box 42)
    - Linguistics (Box 42)
    - Music and Bach (Box 42)
    - American History, 1948-1949 (Box 42)
    - Turner's History Course (Box 42)
    - Medieval Philosophy (Watton) (Box 42)
    - Bible (Lovett) and Philosophy of Religion (Greene), 1949 (Box 42)
    - Notes - Italian in translation (Box 42)
    - 14th Century and Chaucer (Box 42)
    - Notes - Age of Johnson (Hilles) (Box 42)
    - Notes - Victorian Poetry (Purdy) (Box 42)
    - Early Romantic Poets (Pottle), 1949 (Box 42)
    - English Survey (Holden and Knight) (Box 42)
    - Milton - (Witherspoon) (Box 42)
    - Notes - Modern Poetry (Brooks) (Box 42)
    - The Novel (Pickerel) (Box 42)
    - Marlowe and Jonson (M. Allen) (Box 42)
    - 17th Century (Risdon) (Box 42)
    - Robinson, Eliot, Stevens (Morse) (Box 42)
    - Contemporary Literature (Dando), 1955 (Box 42)
    - 17th Century (Sproat) (Box 42)
    - Bibliography (Leisher) (Box 42)
    - Seminar - I.H. White (Box 42)
    - Elizabethan Plays - Loveland (Box 42)
    - Modern Poetry - Sproat (Box 42)
    - Moliere - Racine, etc. (Box 42)
    - PhD. (Box 42)
  - Teaching Stuff, 1957 (Box 42)
  - Bread Loaf, 1957 (Box 42)
  - Lowell, circa 1955; 2 (Box 42)
  - Address Book (Box 42)
  - Notes - 3rd floor to of stairs, 3 (Box 42)
  - Small photograph of Richard Moore, circa 1950s (Box 42)
- Oversize, (1 box)
  - The Histomap of Religion, by John B. Sparks (in Series V) (Box 43)
  - Treasures of Massachusetts, Boston Globe (in Series V) (Box 43)
  - The Histomap of Evolution, by John B. Sparks (in Series V) (Box 43)